AMY CHEN

Seattle, WA | 206-688-0434 | <u>amychen.dev@gmail.com</u> | <u>www.amychen.dev</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/4myc</u> | Blog: <u>dev.to/4myc</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/4myc</u>

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Versatile front-end developer with full-stack capability and a background in graphic and web design. Eager and quick learner keen on utilizing my creative and technical skills to create visually engaging user interfaces and experiences that make users' lives more simple, productive, and entertaining.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONT-END
BACK-END
JavaScript
React.js
PostgreSQL
Ruby
RESTful APIs
HTML
Git
CSS
Material UI
Semantic UI
Bootstrap

DESIGN SKILLS

User Interface Design
Graphic Design
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe InDesign

EDUCATION

10/2019 - 03/2020

Flatiron School

Seattle, WA

Full Stack Web Development In-Person Program

06/2006 - 03/2010

The Art Institute of Seattle

Seattle, WA

BFA, Graphic Design

08/2005 - 05/2006

University of Central Arkansas

Conway, AR General Studies

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Trip Planner

GitHub Client | GitHub Server

Dynamic single-page app that allows a user to create trips and add a packing list and itinerary to each trip.

- + Collaborated with two team members to build the CRUD app within a 7-day timeline
- + Responsibilities: Trips page, new user form, toggle function to view a trip's edit forms, installed Semantic UI, added back-end user validation
- + Utilized Semantic UI interactive elements to style Trips page user interface and improve user experience
- + Front-End: React.js, Semantic UI
- + Back-End: Rails, PostgreSQL

Leopardy! GitHub Repo

Ruby CLI trivia game inspired by Jeopardy! and Pup Quiz from The Tonight Show Starring Jimmy Fallon.

- + Built with Ruby and ActiveRecord within a 4-day timeline
- + Implemented logic to allow the user to create, update, and delete an account
- + Implemented logic to create three game rounds with a question clue and three multiple-choice answer format
- + Incorporated ASCII logo and visual design elements to improve user experience

EXPERIENCE

Bookline Production Assistant Reischling Press Incorporated Tukwila, WA	11/2018 - 09/2019
Production Specialist & Graphic Designer content26 Seattle, WA	09/2010 - 04/2013
Customer Service Representative Minuteman Press Seattle, WA	10/2009 - 01/2010
Graphic Design Intern Washington CEO Magazine Seattle, WA	08/2008 - 09/2008
Graphic Design Intern Titan Seattle, WA	03/2008 - 08/2008